David Mitchell fonds
Simon Fraser University Archives and Records Management Department
David Mitchell fonds
1907 - 1987
F-56
Q100153222
2.5 m of textual records 62 photographs 4 copy negatives
Simon Fraser University Archives and Records Management Department Maggie Benston Student Services Building, Rm. 0400 8888 University Dr. Burnaby British Columbia Canada V5A 1S6 Telephone: 778.782.3805 Email: archives@sfu.ca http://www.sfu.ca/archives
Physical description: 42 photographs located in F-56-7-0-1 Physical description: 20 photographs located in F-56-7-0-2
Mitchell, David
David J. Mitchell is an author, historian, public policy analyst, former Member of the Legislative Assembly of British Columbia, and Vice President, Chief Development Officer of Simon Fraser University. He is the author of W.A.C. Bennett and the Rise of British Columbia.
Born in Montreal in 1954, David J. Mitchell completed a Bachelor of Arts degree in History and Political Science at Simon Fraser University in 1975 and a Master of Arts degree in Canadian History, also at Simon Fraser University, in 1976. In addition, he has completed the Parliamentary Internship Program with the British Columbia Legislature in 1978, and attended the Banff School of Advanced Management in 1988. As of 1999, he is a Doctoral candidate in the Department of History at Simon Fraser University.
David Mitchell's diverse career path has included senior positions in both the public and private sectors. He has served as Deputy Clerk of the Saskatchewan Legislature, and as an Archivist and Editor at the Provincial Archives of British Columbia. In addition, he has held executive positions within the BC resource industries. From 1991 to 1996, David Mitchell served as an independent Member of the Legislative Assembly for West Vancouver – Garibaldi.
David Mitchell is an award-winning writer whose books are well known to British Columbians. He is the author of W.A.C. Bennett and the Rise of British Columbia (1983), considered by many to be the definitive text on W.A.C. Bennett. Bennett, the former premier of British Columbia whose Social Credit government held power between the years of 1952 and 1972, granted Mitchell a number of exclusive interviews between 1976 and 1979, forming the foundation for the subsequent book. David Mitchell is also the author of All Aboard! The Canadian Rockies by Train (1996) and Succession: The Political Reshaping of British Columbia (1987). He has also contributed various articles on public affairs and business to a number of journals, publications and newspapers including the Financial Post, The Globe and Mail, The Vancouver Sun, and Business in Vancouver. In addition, he serves as a frequent commentator on television and radio and has hosted a number of radio and television programs.
published
Full
Revised
Title of the fonds is based on provenance.
Fonds is comprised of research material gathered by David Mitchell for his book, W.A.C. Bennett and the Rise of British Columbia and records generated in the process of completing work on the book. The research material concentrates on Bennett's life as a political figure, the rise of the Social Credit Party, and political issues dealt with by the Bennett government.
It includes a mix of interviews with Bennett and other important political figures of his era, articles, clippings, government documents, Social Credit Party papers, copies of Bennett's personal papers, Mitchell's notes and rough drafts, academic papers, graphic material, and correspondence.
Bennett, W.A.C.; Photographic materials; Textual records; Government; Politics
The fonds was donated by David Mitchell.
All accessions have been processed as of September 2002. No further accruals are expected.
Consult the inventory of the W.A.C. Bennett fonds F-55.
The transcripts in this fonds are photocopies of transcripts held in the British Columbia Archives, which also holds the audio cassettes from which the transcripts were made.
The files are open with no restrictions.
Series descriptions and file lists are available.
- Chapter research, 1907 - 1987; F-56-1; 86 cm of textual records
  published
  Series consists of sources and notes for each chapter. Materials include transcribed interviews, clippings, photocopied articles, government documents, and materials such as correspondence copied from W.A.C. Bennett's personal papers.
  - Chapter 1 - Research Materials, 1907 - 1980; F-56-1-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 56-1)
    Textual records
    Open
  - Chapter 2 - Chapter Draft, [ca 1975] - [ca 1982]; F-56-1-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 56-1)
  - Chapter 2 - Research Materials, 1939 - 1965; F-56-1-0-0-3 (Archival box - standard 56-1)
  - Chapter 3 - Chapter Draft, 1975 - 1982; F-56-1-0-0-4 (Archival box - standard 56-1)
  - Chapter 4 - Chapter Draft, 1975 - 1982; F-56-1-0-0-5 (Archival box - standard 56-1)
  - Chapter 4 - Research Materials, 1943 - 1956; F-56-1-0-0-6 (Archival box - standard 56-1)
  - Chapter 5 - Interviews - W.A.C. Bennett, 1975 - 1979; F-56-1-0-0-7 (Archival box - standard 56-1)
  - Chapter 5 - Interviews - W. Black, 1975 - 1982; F-56-1-0-0-8 (Archival box - standard 56-1)
  - Chapter 5 - Interviews - Robert Bonner, 1975 - 1982; F-56-1-0-0-9 (Archival box - standard 56-1)
  - Chapter 5 - Interviews - Phil Gaglardi, 1975 - 1982; F-56-1-0-0-10 (Archival box - standard 56-1)
  - Chapter 5 - Interviews - Orvis Kennedy, 1975 - 1982; F-56-1-0-0-11 (Archival box - standard 56-1)
  - Chapter 5 - Interviews - W. Kenneth Kiernan, 1977; F-56-1-0-0-12 (Archival box - standard 56-1)
  - Chapter 5 - Interviews - E.C. Manning, 1976 - 1987; F-56-1-0-0-13 (Archival box - standard 56-1)
  - Chapter 5 - Interviews - Eric Martin, 1971 - 1987; F-56-1-0-0-14 (Archival box - standard 56-1)
  - Chapter 5 - Interviews - Peer Paynter, 1976 - [ca 1987]; F-56-1-0-0-15 (Archival box - standard 56-1)
  - Chapter 5 - Interviews - Douglas Turnbull, 1976 - [ca 1987]; F-56-1-0-0-16 (Archival box - standard 56-1)
  - Chapter 5 - Interviews - Clarence Wallace, 1977; F-56-1-0-0-17 (Archival box - standard 56-1)
  - Chapter 5 - Interviews - Lyle Wicks, 1976; F-56-1-0-0-18 (Archival box - standard 56-1)
  - Chapter 5 - Research Materials - Correspondence, 1952 - 1982; F-56-1-0-0-19 (Archival box - standard 56-1)
  - Chapter 6 - Interviews - W.A.C. Bennett, 1976 - 1978; F-56-1-0-0-20 (Archival box - standard 56-1)
  - Chapter 6 - Interviews - W. Black, 1976 - [ca 1982]; F-56-1-0-0-21 (Archival box - standard 56-1)
  - Chapter 6 - Interviews - Robert Bonner, 1976 - [ca 1982]; F-56-1-0-0-22 (Archival box - standard 56-1)
  - Chapter 6 - Interviews - W.N. Chant, 1976 - [ca 1982]; F-56-1-0-0-23 (Archival box - standard 56-1)
  - Chapter 6 - Interviews - John Diefenbaker, 1976 - [ca 1982]; F-56-1-0-0-24 (Archival box - standard 56-1)
  - Chapter 6 - Interviews - C.J. Ferber, 1978; F-56-1-0-0-25 (Archival box - standard 56-1)
  - Chapter 6 - Interviews - Phil Gaglardi, 1975 - [ca 1982]; F-56-1-0-0-26 (Archival box - standard 56-1)
  - Chapter 6 - Interviews - Einar Gunderson, 1975 - [ca 1982]; F-56-1-0-0-27 (Archival box - standard 56-1)
  - Chapter 6 - Interviews - Randolf Harding, 1975 - 1987; F-56-1-0-0-28 (Archival box - standard 56-1)
  - Chapter 6 - Interviews - W. Kenneth Kiernan, 1977; F-56-1-0-0-29 (Archival box - standard 56-1)
  - Chapter 6 - Interviews - Eric Martin, 1971; F-56-1-0-0-30 (Archival box - standard 56-1)
  - Chapter 6 - Interviews - Mayse, 1975 - 1982; F-56-1-0-0-31 (Archival box - standard 56-1)
  - Chapter 6 - Interviews - E.C. Manning, 1975 - 1982; F-56-1-0-0-32 (Archival box - standard 56-1)
  - Chapter 6 - Interviews - Leo Nimsick, 1975 - 1982; F-56-1-0-0-33 (Archival box - standard 56-1)
  - Chapter 6 - Interviews - Peer Paynter, 1975 - 1982; F-56-1-0-0-34 (Archival box - standard 56-1)
  - Chapter 6 - Interviews - Lyle Wicks, 1975 - 1982; F-56-1-0-0-35 (Archival box - standard 56-1)
  - Chapter 6 - Interviews - Ray Williston, 1975 - 1982; F-56-1-0-0-36 (Archival box - standard 56-1)
  - Chapter 6 - Interviews - Harold Winch, 1975 - 1982; F-56-1-0-0-37 (Archival box - standard 56-1)
  - Chapter 6 - Interviews - Clarence Wallace, 1971 - [ca 1982]; F-56-1-0-0-38 (Archival box - standard 56-1)
  - Chapter 6 - Research Material - Articles, 1952 - 1954; F-56-1-0-0-39 (Archival box - standard 56-2)
  - Chapter 6 - Research Material - Correspondence, 1952; F-56-1-0-0-40 (Archival box - standard 56-2)
  - Chapter 6 - Research Material - Documents, 1957 - 1980; F-56-1-0-0-41 (Archival box - standard 56-2)
  - Chapter 6 - Research Material - Speeches, 1952; F-56-1-0-0-42 (Archival box - standard 56-2)
  - Chapter 6 - Research Material - Notes, 1975 - 1982; F-56-1-0-0-43 (Archival box - standard 56-2)
  - Chapter 7 - Interviews - W.A.C. Bennett, 1977; F-56-1-0-0-44 (Archival box - standard 56-2)
  - Chapter 7 - Interviews - W. Black, 1975 - 1982; F-56-1-0-0-45 (Archival box - standard 56-2)
  - Chapter 7 - Interviews - Robert Bonner, 1980; F-56-1-0-0-46 (Archival box - standard 56-2)
  - Chapter 7 - Interviews - Donald Brothers, 1975 - 1982; F-56-1-0-0-47 (Archival box - standard 56-2)
  - Chapter 7 - Interviews - Phil Gaglardi, 1978; F-56-1-0-0-48 (Archival box - standard 56-2)
  - Chapter 7 - Interviews - Randolph Harding, 1978; F-56-1-0-0-49 (Archival box - standard 56-2)
  - Chapter 7 - Interviews - J. Gordon Gibson, 1960 - 1977; F-56-1-0-0-50 (Archival box - standard 56-2)
  - Chapter 7 - Interviews - W. Kenneth Kiernan, 1977; F-56-1-0-0-51 (Archival box - standard 56-2)
  - Chapter 7 - Interviews - Leo Nimsick, 1975 - 1982; F-56-1-0-0-52 (Archival box - standard 56-2)
  - Chapter 7 - Interviews - Waldo Skillings, 1977; F-56-1-0-0-53 (Archival box - standard 56-2)
  - Chapter 7 - Interviews - Robert M Strachan, 1978; F-56-1-0-0-54 (Archival box - standard 56-2)
  - Chapter 7 - Interviews - J.O. Wilson, 1979; F-56-1-0-0-55 (Archival box - standard 56-2)
  - Chapter 7 - Interviews - Ray Williston, 1975; F-56-1-0-0-56 (Archival box - standard 56-2)
  - Chapter 7 - Research Material - Articles, 1957 - 1976; F-56-1-0-0-57 (Archival box - standard 56-2)
  - Chapter 7 - Research Material - Correspondence, 1952 - 1956; F-56-1-0-0-58 (Archival box - standard 56-2)
  - Chapter 7 - Research Material - Documents, 1952 - 1956; F-56-1-0-0-59 (Archival box - standard 56-2)
  - Chapter 7 - Research Material - Notes, 1970 - 1972; F-56-1-0-0-60 (Archival box - standard 56-2)
  - Chapter 8 - Interviews - W.A.C. Bennett, 1977; F-56-1-0-0-61 (Archival box - standard 56-3)
  - Chapter 8 - Interviews - W. Black, 1975 - 1982; F-56-1-0-0-62 (Archival box - standard 56-3)
  - Chapter 8 - Interviews - Robert Bonner, 1975 - 1982; F-56-1-0-0-63 (Archival box - standard 56-3)
  - Chapter 8 - Interviews - Donald Brothers, 1978; F-56-1-0-0-64 (Archival box - standard 56-3)
  - Chapter 8 - Interviews - W.N. Chant, 1975 - 1982; F-56-1-0-0-65 (Archival box - standard 56-3)
  - Chapter 8 - Interviews - Dan Ekman, 1975 - 1982; F-56-1-0-0-66 (Archival box - standard 56-3)
  - Chapter 8 - Interviews - Phil Gaglardi, 1978; F-56-1-0-0-67 (Archival box - standard 56-3)
  - Chapter 8 - Interviews - Einar Gunderson, 1977; F-56-1-0-0-68 (Archival box - standard 56-3)
  - Chapter 8 - Interviews - W. Kenneth Kiernan, 1977; F-56-1-0-0-69 (Archival box - standard 56-3)
  - Chapter 8 - Interviews - Eric Martin, 1975 - 1982; F-56-1-0-0-70 (Archival box - standard 56-3)
  - Chapter 8 - Interviews - Leo Nimsick, 1978; F-56-1-0-0-71 (Archival box - standard 56-3)
  - Chapter 8 - Interviews - Alexander Peabody, 1978; F-56-1-0-0-72 (Archival box - standard 56-3)
  - Chapter 8 - Interviews - Leslie Peterson, 1975 - 1982; F-56-1-0-0-73 (Archival box - standard 56-3)
  - Chapter 8 - Interviews - Robert M. Strachan, 1978; F-56-1-0-0-74 (Archival box - standard 56-3)
  - Chapter 8 - Interviews - Lyle Wicks, 1975 - 1982; F-56-1-0-0-75 (Archival box - standard 56-3)
  - Chapter 8 - Interviews - Ray Williston, 1975; F-56-1-0-0-76 (Archival box - standard 56-3)
  - Chapter 8 - Research Materials - Articles, 1975 - 1982; F-56-1-0-0-77 (Archival box - standard 56-3)
  - Chapter 8 - Research Materials - Correspondence, 1960; F-56-1-0-0-78 (Archival box - standard 56-3)
  - Chapter 8 - Research Materials - Documents, 1982; F-56-1-0-0-79 (Archival box - standard 56-3)
  - Chapter 8 - Research Materials - Published Sources, 1975 - 1982; F-56-1-0-0-80 (Archival box - standard 56-3)
  - Chapter 8 - Research Materials - Speeches, 1953 - 1959; F-56-1-0-0-81 (Archival box - standard 56-3)
  - Chapter 8 - Research Materials - Notes, 1977; F-56-1-0-0-82 (Archival box - standard 56-3)
  - Chapter 9 - Interviews - W.A.C. Bennett 1/2, 1976 - 1977; F-56-1-0-0-83 (Archival box - standard 56-3)
  - Chapter 9 - Interviews - W.A.C. Bennett 2/2, 1977 - 1978; F-56-1-0-0-84 (Archival box - standard 56-3)
  - Chapter 9 - Interviews - Robert Bonner, 1975 - 1982; F-56-1-0-0-85 (Archival box - standard 56-4)
  - Chapter 9 - Interviews - John Diefenbaker, 1975 - 1982; F-56-1-0-0-86 (Archival box - standard 56-4)
  - Chapter 9 - Interviews - David Croll, 1978; F-56-1-0-0-87 (Archival box - standard 56-4)
  - Chapter 9 - Interviews - Davie Fulton, 1975 - 1982; F-56-1-0-0-88 (Archival box - standard 56-4)
  - Chapter 9 - Interviews - Dan Ekman, 1975 - 1982; F-56-1-0-0-89 (Archival box - standard 56-4)
  - Chapter 9 - Interviews - Phil Gaglardi, 1975 - 1982; F-56-1-0-0-90 (Archival box - standard 56-4)
  - Chapter 9 - Interviews - Randolph Harding, 1975 - 1982; F-56-1-0-0-91 (Archival box - standard 56-4)
  - Chapter 9 - Interviews - Leslie Peterson, 1975 - 1982; F-56-1-0-0-92 (Archival box - standard 56-4)
  - Chapter 9 - Interviews - Robert M. Strachan, 1975 - 1982; F-56-1-0-0-93 (Archival box - standard 56-4)
  - Chapter 9 - Interviews - Ray Williston, 1975 - 1982; F-56-1-0-0-94 (Archival box - standard 56-4)
  - Chapter 9 - Articles - Columbia River Treaty, 1957 - 1979; F-56-1-0-0-95 (Archival box - standard 56-4)
  - Chapter 9 - Correspondence - Columbia River Treaty, 1944 - 1963; F-56-1-0-0-96 (Archival box - standard 56-4)
  - Chapter 9 - Speeches and Press Releases - C.R.T., 1961 - 1974; F-56-1-0-0-97 (Archival box - standard 56-4)
  - Chapter 9 - Printed Sources - Columbia River Treaty, 1973 - 1979; F-56-1-0-0-98 (Archival box - standard 56-4)
    Restricted in part
  - Chapter 9 - B.C. Electric Takeover, 1961 - 1963; F-56-1-0-0-99 (Archival box - standard 56-4)
  - Chapter 9 - Bank of British Columbia 1/2, 1964; F-56-1-0-0-100 (Archival box - standard 56-4)
  - Chapter 9 - Bank of British Columbia 2/2, 1964; F-56-1-0-0-101 (Archival box - standard 56-4)
  - Chapter 9 - Notes, 1975 - 1982; F-56-1-0-0-102 (Archival box - standard 56-4)
  - Chapter 10 - Interviews - W.A.C. Bennett, 1975 - 1982; F-56-1-0-0-103 (Archival box - standard 56-5)
  - Chapter 10 - Interviews - W. Black, 1975 - 1982; F-56-1-0-0-104 (Archival box - standard 56-5)
  - Chapter 10 - Interviews - Robert Bonner, 1980; F-56-1-0-0-105 (Archival box - standard 56-5)
  - Chapter 10 - Interviews - Donald Brothers, 1975 - 1982; F-56-1-0-0-106 (Archival box - standard 56-5)
  - Chapter 10 - Interviews - Dan Campbell, 1975 - 1982; F-56-1-0-0-107 (Archival box - standard 56-5)
  - Chapter 10 - Interviews - W.N. Chant, 1975 - 1982; F-56-1-0-0-108 (Archival box - standard 56-5)
  - Chapter 10 - Interviews - William Clancey, 1975 - 1982; F-56-1-0-0-109 (Archival box - standard 56-5)
  - Chapter 10 - Interviews - John Diefenbaker, 1975 - 1982; F-56-1-0-0-110 (Archival box - standard 56-5)
  - Chapter 10 - Interviews - Dan Ekman, 1978; F-56-1-0-0-111 (Archival box - standard 56-5)
  - Chapter 10 - Interviews - J.F.K. English, 1975 - 1982; F-56-1-0-0-112 (Archival box - standard 56-5)
  - Chapter 10 - Interviews - Phil Gaglardi, 1978; F-56-1-0-0-113 (Archival box - standard 56-5)
  - Chapter 10 - Interviews - Einar Gunderson, 1975 - 1982; F-56-1-0-0-114 (Archival box - standard 56-5)
  - Chapter 10 - Interviews - Randolph Harding, 1975 - 1982; F-56-1-0-0-115 (Archival box - standard 56-5)
  - Chapter 10 - Interviews - Cam Kenmuir, 1975 - 1982; F-56-1-0-0-116 (Archival box - standard 56-5)
  - Chapter 10 - Interviews - Ralph Loffmark, 1975 - 1982; F-56-1-0-0-117 (Archival box - standard 56-5)
  - Chapter 10 - Interviews - E.C. Manning, 1975 - 1982; F-56-1-0-0-118 (Archival box - standard 56-5)
  - Chapter 10 - Interviews - Leo Nimsick, 1975 - 1982; F-56-1-0-0-119 (Archival box - standard 56-5)
  - Chapter 10 - Interviews - Leslie Peterson, 1975 - 1982; F-56-1-0-0-120 (Archival box - standard 56-5)
  - Chapter 10 - Interviews - Waldo Skillings, 1975 - 1982; F-56-1-0-0-121 (Archival box - standard 56-5)
  - Chapter 10 - Interviews - Robert M. Strachan, 1975 - 1982; F-56-1-0-0-122 (Archival box - standard 56-5)
  - Chapter 10 - Interviews - Robert Thompson, 1975 - 1982; F-56-1-0-0-123 (Archival box - standard 56-5)
  - Chapter 10 - Interviews - Ray Williston, 1975; F-56-1-0-0-124 (Archival box - standard 56-5)
  - Chapter 10 - Newspaper Articles, 1958 - 1979; F-56-1-0-0-125 (Archival box - standard 56-5)
  - Chapter 10 - Magazine Articles, 1962 - 1986; F-56-1-0-0-126 (Archival box - standard 56-5)
  - Chapter 10 - Correspondence, 1957 - 1964; F-56-1-0-0-127 (Archival box - standard 56-5)
  - Chapter 10 - Printed Sources, 1977; F-56-1-0-0-128 (Archival box - standard 56-5)
  - Chapter 10 - Speeches, 1961 - 1967; F-56-1-0-0-129 (Archival box - standard 56-5)
  - Chapter 10 - Notes, 1975 - 1982; F-56-1-0-0-130 (Archival box - standard 56-5)
  - Chapter 11 - Interviews - Bill Bennett, 1977; F-56-1-0-0-131 (Archival box - standard 56-6)
  - Chapter 11 - Interviews - W.A.C. Bennett, 1970 - 1972; F-56-1-0-0-132 (Archival box - standard 56-6)
  - Chapter 11 - Interviews - Robert Bonner, 1975 - 1982; F-56-1-0-0-133 (Archival box - standard 56-6)
  - Chapter 11 - Interviews - Donald Brothers, 1978; F-56-1-0-0-134 (Archival box - standard 56-6)
  - Chapter 11 - Interviews - Dan Campbell, 1975 - 1982; F-56-1-0-0-135 (Archival box - standard 56-6)
  - Chapter 11 - Interviews - Herb Capozzi, 1975 - 1982; F-56-1-0-0-136 (Archival box - standard 56-6)
  - Chapter 11 - Interviews - W.N. Chant, 1975 - 1982; F-56-1-0-0-137 (Archival box - standard 56-6)
  - Chapter 11 - Interviews - William Clancey, 1975 - 1982; F-56-1-0-0-138 (Archival box - standard 56-6)
  - Chapter 11 - Interviews - Winnifred Earl, 1975 - 1982; F-56-1-0-0-139 (Archival box - standard 56-6)
  - Chapter 11 - Interviews - Dan Ekman, 1975 - 1982; F-56-1-0-0-140 (Archival box - standard 56-6)
  - Chapter 11 - Interviews - Einar Gunderson, 1975 - 1982; F-56-1-0-0-141 (Archival box - standard 56-6)
  - Chapter 11 - Interviews - Cam Kenmuir, 1975 - 1982; F-56-1-0-0-142 (Archival box - standard 56-6)
  - Chapter 11 - Interviews - W. Kenneth Kiernan, 1977; F-56-1-0-0-143 (Archival box - standard 56-6)
  - Chapter 11 - Interviews - Ralph Loffmark, 1975 - 1982; F-56-1-0-0-144 (Archival box - standard 56-6)
  - Chapter 11 - Interviews - Katherine Mylrea, 1978; F-56-1-0-0-145 (Archival box - standard 56-6)
  - Chapter 11 - Interviews - Leslie Peterson, 1978; F-56-1-0-0-146 (Archival box - standard 56-6)
  - Chapter 11 - Interviews - Robert Wenman, 1975 - 1982; F-56-1-0-0-147 (Archival box - standard 56-6)
  - Chapter 11 - Interviews - Ray Williston, 1975 - 1982; F-56-1-0-0-148 (Archival box - standard 56-6)
  - Chapter 11 - Newspaper Articles, 1964 - 1970; F-56-1-0-0-149 (Archival box - standard 56-6)
  - Chapter 11 - Newspaper Articles, 1972 - 1981; F-56-1-0-0-150 (Archival box - standard 56-6)
  - Chapter 11 - Magazine Articles, 1965 - 1980; F-56-1-0-0-151 (Archival box - standard 56-6)
  - Chapter 11 - Correspondence, 1968 - 1972; F-56-1-0-0-152 (Archival box - standard 56-6)
  - Chapter 11 - Documents, 1973; F-56-1-0-0-153 (Archival box - standard 56-6)
  - Chapter 11 - Printed Sources, 1963 - 1981; F-56-1-0-0-154 (Archival box - standard 56-6)
  - Chapter 11 - Notes, 1972 - 1978; F-56-1-0-0-155 (Archival box - standard 56-6)
  - Chapter 12 - Interviews - W.A.C. Bennett, 1975 - 1976; F-56-1-0-0-156 (Archival box - standard 56-7)
  - Chapter 12 - Interviews - W. Black, 1975; F-56-1-0-0-157 (Archival box - standard 56-7)
  - Chapter 12 - Interviews - Donald Brothers, 1975; F-56-1-0-0-158 (Archival box - standard 56-7)
  - Chapter 12 - Interviews - Dan Campbell, 1975 - 1982; F-56-1-0-0-159 (Archival box - standard 56-7)
  - Chapter 12 - Interviews - Herb Capozzi, 1975 - 1982; F-56-1-0-0-160 (Archival box - standard 56-7)
  - Chapter 12 - Interviews - W.N. Chant, 1975 - 1982; F-56-1-0-0-161 (Archival box - standard 56-7)
  - Chapter 12 - Interviews - William Clancey, 1975 - 1982; F-56-1-0-0-162 (Archival box - standard 56-7)
  - Chapter 12 - Interviews - Phil Gaglardi, 1975 - 1982; F-56-1-0-0-163 (Archival box - standard 56-7)
  - Chapter 12 - Interviews - Dan Ekman, 1975 - 1982; F-56-1-0-0-164 (Archival box - standard 56-7)
  - Chapter 12 - Interviews - Leslie Peterson, 1975 - 1982; F-56-1-0-0-165 (Archival box - standard 56-7)
  - Chapter 12 - Interviews - Waldo Skillings, 1977; F-56-1-0-0-166 (Archival box - standard 56-7)
  - Chapter 12 - Interviews - Derril Warren, 1978; F-56-1-0-0-167 (Archival box - standard 56-7)
  - Chapter 12 - Interviews - Ray Williston, 1975 - 1982; F-56-1-0-0-168 (Archival box - standard 56-7)
  - Chapter 12 - Newspaper Articles, 1968 - 1974; F-56-1-0-0-169 (Archival box - standard 56-7)
  - Chapter 12 - Magazine Articles, 1969 - 1977; F-56-1-0-0-170 (Archival box - standard 56-7)
  - Chapter 12 - Documents and Correspondence, 1972 - 1973; F-56-1-0-0-171 (Archival box - standard 56-7)
  - Chapter 12 - Printed Sources, 1972 - 1980; F-56-1-0-0-172 (Archival box - standard 56-7)
  - Chapter 12 - Notes, 1977 - 1978; F-56-1-0-0-173 (Archival box - standard 56-7)
  - Notes, 1965; F-56-1-0-0-174 (Archival box - standard 56-7)
  - Notes, 1965; F-56-1-0-0-175 (Archival box - standard 56-7)
  - Notes, 1963 - 1965; F-56-1-0-0-176 (Archival box - standard 56-7)
- Bennett and Social Credit Party background, 1939 - 1982; F-56-2; 18 cm of textual records
  Series consists of materials relating to W.A.C. Bennett's family background and to the development of the Social Credit Party in B.C. Includes transcribed interviews with family members, copied documents such as death certificates, copies of Social Credit Party papers, copies of Bennett's speeches, interviews with Bennett, and research correspondence.
  - Bennett Family, 1977 - 1982; F-56-2-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 56-8)
  - Bill Bennett, 1978; F-56-2-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 56-8)
  - May Bennett, 1978; F-56-2-0-0-3 (Archival box - standard 56-8)
  - Russell Bennett, 1978; F-56-2-0-0-4 (Archival box - standard 56-8)
  - Winnifred Earl, 1978; F-56-2-0-0-5 (Archival box - standard 56-8)
  - Anita Tozer, 1977; F-56-2-0-0-6 (Archival box - standard 56-8)
  - Tony Tozer, 1978; F-56-2-0-0-7 (Archival box - standard 56-8)
  - W.A.C. Bennett's Early Years, 1978 - 1981; F-56-2-0-0-8 (Archival box - standard 56-8)
  - W.A.C. Bennett, 1939 - 1971; F-56-2-0-0-9 (Archival box - standard 56-8)
  - W.A.C. Bennett, 1943 - 1944; F-56-2-0-0-10 (Archival box - standard 56-8)
  - W.A.C. Bennett, 1945 - 1956; F-56-2-0-0-10.1 (Archival box - standard 56-8)
  - W.A.C. Bennett RE: Columbia River Treaty, 1963 - 1964; F-56-2-0-0-11 (Archival box - standard 56-8)
  - W.A.C. Bennett Travel, 1965 - 1966; F-56-2-0-0-12 (Archival box - standard 56-8)
  - Public Archives of British Columbia Materials, 1971 - 1978; F-56-2-0-0-13 (Archival box - standard 56-8)
  - C.B.C. Materials, 1981; F-56-2-0-0-14 (Archival box - standard 56-8)
  - W.A.C. Bennett Speeches, 1964; F-56-2-0-0-15 (Archival box - standard 56-8)
  - MacLean's Interview, 1975; F-56-2-0-0-16 (Archival box - standard 56-8)
  - Research Correspondence, 1976; F-56-2-0-0-17 (Archival box - standard 56-8)
  - W.A.C. Bennett, 1978; F-56-2-0-0-18 (Archival box - standard 56-9)
  - W.A.C. Bennett, 1976 - 1979; F-56-2-0-0-19 (Archival box - standard 56-9)